<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>biographies on Isaac Lopez</title>
    <link>https://rilopez.com/tags/biographies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in biographies on Isaac Lopez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 23:01:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rilopez.com/tags/biographies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Life And Work</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/my-life-and-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 23:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/my-life-and-work/</guid>
      <description>Father was Farmer, Herny was more interested in using machines to do the work. Started by repairing watches, and although he liked the engineering craftsmanship required to make a great watch he had the preference to work on machines that help to make and activity more efficient.
Power and machinery, money and goods, are useful only as they set us free to live. They are but means to an end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kissinger: A Biography</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/kissinger-a-biography/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 13:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/kissinger-a-biography/</guid>
      <description>WII German Refuge, Academic, Womanizer, Foreign policy expert
Real politik based on practical rather than moral or ideological considerations, countries that act according to ideals instead of real interest are dangerous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idea Makers by Stephen Woldfram</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/idea-makers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 11:00:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/idea-makers/</guid>
      <description>I just read the book Idea Makers: Personal Perspectives on the lives Ideas of some notable People by Stephen Wolfram and it is amazing. Here some of my takeaways
  John von Newumann: when John died He left his daughter a Box that should be opened on the 50th anniversary of his death, his Daughter emailed Stephen that disappointingly the box was not John von Newman&amp;rsquo;s at all!
  There is a lot much more about Ada Lovelace, the first programmer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Total Recall My Unbelievably true life story</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/total-recall/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 04:19:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/total-recall/</guid>
      <description>One of the first movies that I watch in a beta video format was Terminator, I remember going to my friends house, it was amazing, a very real Robot killing everyone was very memorable for my young mind. One of the scenes I remember the most was when the terminator steals a car, Arnold describes that that scene was filmed without city permission and very quick.
Arnold have had an exceptional life, one of the anecdotes I liked the most was after being questioned about a hidden message (I, F, Y) to lawmakers, and that it could not be a coincidence because the chance of that happened by coincide was very low, Arnold answered by asking</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leonardo Da Vinci</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/leonardo-da-vinci/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 04:54:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/leonardo-da-vinci/</guid>
      <description>Any Walter Isaacson&amp;rsquo;s biography is a warranty of delivering a bio research with story-telling structure and, This book was not the exception.
Although a lot has been writing about Leonardo Da Vinci, I was only familiar with his amazing notebooks and his famous paintings, but little I new about other important parts of this life like:
 Niccolò Machiavelli was his close friend. Closes a job request letter (to Ludovico Sforza) with something like &amp;ldquo;By the Way I am also a painter&amp;rdquo; Was an eternal procastinator His most important talent was his observation skills  You can find out more about the book on</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>