<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Isaac Lopez</title>
    <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Isaac Lopez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 18:47:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rilopez.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New Creators</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/new-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 11:56:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/new-content/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joe Rogan at Lex Podcast</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/joe-rogan-at-lex-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 23:19:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/joe-rogan-at-lex-podcast/</guid>
      <description>My takeaways  Ideas breath in brains of humans.  You just need to show up Joe Recommends Book The War of Art: Winning the Inner Creative Battle  sit down and do the work, as a professional and wait for the muse (the idea) and let you know what to do.     Joe met Jamie at the ice house  he is unique , has little ego &amp;amp; is a great sound eng   What is the meaning of life?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neuralink Summer 2020</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/neuralink-summer-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 23:40:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/neuralink-summer-2020/</guid>
      <description>My takeaways  Neuralink had a great streaming showing their latest updates they showed live telemetry directly from an alive walking pig Pigs are similar to people, they move a lot and they are robust so if the device does not get malfunctions on pigs , it would work on people Currently the team is 100 people, it is expected to grow up to 10K people the device uses something like bluetooth Clinical trial is aimed at people with paraplegia In the future you can record your memories and play it back, How do we know that this moment is not our future self playing back his memories?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallel and Asynchronous Programming with Streams and CompletableFuture by Venkat Subramaniam</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/parallel-and-asynchronous-programming-venkat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 17:39:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/parallel-and-asynchronous-programming-venkat/</guid>
      <description>    parallel when you have an array of data concurrent when you have a problem that can be divided an conquer. Collection Pipeline pattern by Martin Flower forEachOrdered  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microservices by Martin Flowler</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/microservices-by-martin-flowler/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 11:24:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/microservices-by-martin-flowler/</guid>
      <description>My takeaways:   There is no real definition, Its something that from the begining is ill defined
  Martin can identify 9 characteristics
 Componentization via services Thinking about parts not as builders, but as users changing parts of stereo components Organized Around Business capabilities Smart endpoints and dump pipes. There is no room for complex middleware (ESB) Decentralized governance Decentraliced Data Managment Infraestructure automation Design for failure    Are microservices just SOA?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Terrible Ideas Weakening Gen Z by Jonathan Haidt</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/three-terrible-ideas-weakening-gen-z-by-jonathan-haidt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 07:12:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/three-terrible-ideas-weakening-gen-z-by-jonathan-haidt/</guid>
      <description>My Takeaways   Two disorders have been growing between generation Z
 Emotional disorders: depression and anxiety Political polarization    The sudden emergence of a new moral culture of safetyism (safespaces,trigger warinings, )
  What does not kill you makes you weaker
    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academy Lessons Learned</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/academy-lessons-learned/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 14:56:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/academy-lessons-learned/</guid>
      <description>Nearsoft Academy: Lessons learned after almost a decade preparing interns With a tight talent market, developing talent in-house gets a special appeal. Not only because of the reduction of costs but for the opportunity to rise the bar for future generations. Some assumptions anybody makes when trying to implement an internship program are,
 We can ask our seniors to mentor interns We are better at teaching than their university professors With the right training program any college graduate can produce good work at our organization  After almost a decade of working with interns, at Nearsoft academy We learned a lot of hard lessons that help us to get rid of those assumptions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Finances With Ledger</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/personal-finances-with-ledger/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 16:46:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/personal-finances-with-ledger/</guid>
      <description>Where my money went this time? That is always my question every time I take a look to my monthly bank statements. Over the years I have tried several apps and methods to reduce the panic we get when we have no idea how we acquired that credit card debt, Although all the options have its pros &amp;amp; cons, commonly they share the same problem of locking your data to their chooses proprietary format, giving you the risk of not being able to read when the online service disappears or the app no longer run on newer OS or devises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nearsoft Academy</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/nearsoft-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 21:42:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/nearsoft-academy/</guid>
      <description>8 years ago I started the foundations of our internship program at nearsoft, called Nearsoft Academy. So far 91 young engineers have taken the program, most of them worked for us right after graduation.
Designing an internship program Because I think that a software engineer is most about people than about &amp;ldquo;techy stuff&amp;rdquo;, I tried to design the program following the teachings several books like fearless change, pragmatic programmer, outliers &amp;amp; code complete</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile Is Dead by Dave Thomas</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/agile-is-dead-by-dave-thomas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 21:46:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/agile-is-dead-by-dave-thomas/</guid>
      <description>My Takeaways   UML destroyed the OOP by focusing a generation of programmers into Classes instead of objects.
  Agile is not a noun, it is an adjective
  Fear sells: new words, new roles, new ways to measure, are we doing it right?
  Cool sells: bright &amp;amp; Shiny, feeling the power, What!!, you aren&amp;rsquo;t doing Agile!!
  Agile is an industry, that taxes us in terms of fear</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Mindfulness on Your Brain and Business by Dr Amishi jha</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/impact-of-mindfulness-on-your-brain-and-business-by-dr-amishi-hjha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 11:10:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/impact-of-mindfulness-on-your-brain-and-business-by-dr-amishi-hjha/</guid>
      <description>   My Takeaways  Presenter is Mario galarreta works in the people development team [23:50] Mindfulness is a mental mode characterized by attention to present moment experience without conceptual elaboration or emotional reactivity. [24:00] Be in the here and now without an story about it  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deliberate Practices for programmers</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/deliberate-practices-for-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 02:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/deliberate-practices-for-programmers/</guid>
      <description>Per Dayra Chiu recommendation , last year I read the book Peak: Secrets from the New Science of Expertise by by K. Anders Ericsson &amp;amp; Robert Pool. I didn&amp;rsquo;t imagine how much gold I would find in that book. the topic that surprised the most was: Deliberate practices
First, what is deliberate practice? Is a special type of practice that is purposeful and systematic. It is highly demanding mentally so it requires high levels of focus and concentration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impediment to Action Advances Action</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/impediment-to-action-advances-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 15:33:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/impediment-to-action-advances-action/</guid>
      <description>While it is true that someone can impede our actions, they can not impede our intentions and our attitudes, which have the power of being conditional and adaptable. For the Mind converts any obstacle to its action into means of achieving it. That which is an impediment to action advances action , What stands in the way becomes the way
Marcus Aurelius, Meditations 5.20
 How many times we forget this?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philosophy Is for Life</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/philosophy-is-for-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 12:58:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/philosophy-is-for-life/</guid>
      <description>Philosophy is not a trick to catch the public; it is not devised for show. it is non concerned with words, but with facts. It&amp;rsquo;s not employed for some pleasure before day is spent, or to relieve the uneasiness of our leisure. It shape and built up the soul, it gives order to live guides action, shows what should and shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be done. &amp;ndash; it sits at the rudder steering our course as we vacillate in uncertanties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toma Al Toro Por Los Cuernos</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/toma-al-toro-por-los-cuernos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 12:38:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/toma-al-toro-por-los-cuernos/</guid>
      <description>You have endured countless troubles &amp;ndash; all for not letting your ruling reason do the work it was made for&amp;ndash; Enough already &amp;mdash; Marcus Aurelius, Meditations, 9.26
 In Spanish there is this saying &amp;ldquo;toma al toro por los cuernos&amp;rdquo; to indicate to take charge of the problem/issue/task in front. In this quote Marcus indicate that we should do it always using our ruling reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linda Rising Interview</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/linda-rising-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/linda-rising-interview/</guid>
      <description>I read the book fearless change almost 8 years ago and since then I have been a big follower of Linda Rising teachings. Because one of my new-year resolutions was to meet at least one of my heros, I asked Carlos (from dojo live) to help me talk to Linda Rising, I was not hoping he could get her as a guess in dojo live,.. ohh I was very very wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning new tricks - JHipster: AngularJS, Spring Boot</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/jaimito-el-cartero-oriented-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/jaimito-el-cartero-oriented-programming/</guid>
      <description>I have always thought that the best motivator to learn something is when somebody pays you for doing it (indirectly). Last year I accepted a small freelance project just because it would be a good oportinity to sharp skills and add something new to my bag of tricks. Since for sometime I have been using some &amp;ldquo;outdated&amp;rdquo; things (Ember.js, ColdFusion, Node.js , YUI Library), so I thought &amp;ldquo;it would be cool to use something &amp;ldquo;mainstream/popular&amp;rdquo; with younger developers, and I got surprised because I found something that had all of that and it was a cool name: JHipster</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> </title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/what-you-are-really-meant-to-do-by-robert-steven-kaplan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 16:36:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/what-you-are-really-meant-to-do-by-robert-steven-kaplan/</guid>
      <description>My takeaways   Speaker Robert Steven Kaplan
  &amp;ldquo;reaching your potential is a never ending activity&amp;rdquo;
  &amp;ldquo;it is like being fit or healthy&amp;rdquo;
  You are not able to known your weakness. you need help from other people because we all have blind spots. ask for feedback on your weakness
  Why people fail (most commonly)?
 Isolation Inability to learn    Knowing your self</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confessions of a Public Speaker by Scott Berkun</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/confessions-of-a-public-speaker-by-scott-berkun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2009 12:59:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/confessions-of-a-public-speaker-by-scott-berkun/</guid>
      <description>My takeaways   Confessions of a public speaker book
  6 reason of sucking at public speaking and how to fix it
  Your are afraid of the crowd.Physical exercise that day
  This is your first time. You&amp;rsquo;ve practiced till it&amp;rsquo;s good
  You are a turtle on drugs. There is a rhythm I can follow
 Rhythm is important ( not so fast, not so slow ) most people attention span is between 5 to 10 min, your talk should be sorted in segments of 5-10 mins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Energy Project by Tony Schwartz</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/the-energy-project-by-tony-schwartz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2009 15:50:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/the-energy-project-by-tony-schwartz/</guid>
      <description>My Takeaways  Time is finite  Energy is expandable Energy is the capacity to do work.   4 sources of energy on a human:  physical (cuantum): nutrition, fitness, sleep, recovery. Emotional (Quality): how do you feel. Mental (Focus): one thing on a time, we are not multitasking. The Human Spirit (Purpose): aligment what you say its important and how you do   Renewal of energy its important, quality its the most important  Ultradian rhythms the 90-120 minute wave Paradigm Shift: Life as sprinter not a marathoner   To manage energy Optimally , we most build positive rituals    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Arms, No Legs, No Worries by Nick Vujicic </title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/no-arms-no-legs-no-worries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2009 16:32:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/no-arms-no-legs-no-worries/</guid>
      <description>My takeaways  Be grateful with what you are Do not think on what you do not have, think on what you have. Disabled is just in the mind Ask for a second opinion when somebody give you a bad opinion The day you think you reached your full potential, is the day when you haven&amp;rsquo;t done it. Live a life without limits    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marshall Goldsmith | Talk @ google</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/marshall-goldsmith-leading-at-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2009 08:57:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/marshall-goldsmith-leading-at-google/</guid>
      <description>I just discovered Marshall Goldsmith and he is awesome, looking forward to read his book What got you here, won&amp;rsquo;t get you there. Here are my takeaways:
 We spend a lot of time helping leaders learn what to do, we don&amp;rsquo;t spend enough time helping leaders learn what to stop -Peter Drucker WINNING TO MUCH, we are so competitive that we argue who is more miserable &amp;ldquo;help more, judge less&amp;rdquo; Use little amounts of money to produce change in behavior We only can change what we want to change.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>