<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>learning on Isaac Lopez</title>
    <link>https://rilopez.com/tags/learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in learning on Isaac Lopez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 02:15:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rilopez.com/tags/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Make It Stick: The Science of Successful Learning</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/make-it-stick/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 02:15:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/make-it-stick/</guid>
      <description>Some random general highlights
 The most important is to fight forgetfulness. Learning styles is a myth, there are preferences but there is not true that some people learn better with a given kind of material (listening, reading, etc) Recalling and reflection is better than massive practice, the later gives the illusion of knowing by familiarizing the student with the material but the forgetfulness is quicker  Learning is misunderstood when we ask people about the best(preferred) learning method, most people will answer that it would be re-reading and highlight the material, but this approach is not backed up by data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peak Secrets From New Science of Expertise</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/peak-secrets-from-new-science-of-expertise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 02:46:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/peak-secrets-from-new-science-of-expertise/</guid>
      <description>Some random hightlights   Anything can be learned with a good designed deliverate practice
  the 10,000 hours myth (popularized by Malcom Gladwell) has been doing more harm than good, because it is not the time you put into something but how &amp;amp; what you practice
  deliberate practice is how anything can be learn. the components of a deliberate practice are:
 A well defined practice plan, with small steps or goals Proper Feedback (in a timely manner) Monitor your progress Mantain motivation Full Attention Mental Models should be considered    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deliberate Practices for programmers</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/deliberate-practices-for-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 02:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/deliberate-practices-for-programmers/</guid>
      <description>Per Dayra Chiu recommendation , last year I read the book Peak: Secrets from the New Science of Expertise by by K. Anders Ericsson &amp;amp; Robert Pool. I didn&amp;rsquo;t imagine how much gold I would find in that book. the topic that surprised the most was: Deliberate practices
First, what is deliberate practice? Is a special type of practice that is purposeful and systematic. It is highly demanding mentally so it requires high levels of focus and concentration.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>