<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>leadership on Isaac Lopez</title>
    <link>https://rilopez.com/tags/leadership/</link>
    <description>Recent content in leadership on Isaac Lopez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2009 15:50:54 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rilopez.com/tags/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Energy Project by Tony Schwartz</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/the-energy-project-by-tony-schwartz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2009 15:50:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/the-energy-project-by-tony-schwartz/</guid>
      <description>   My Takeaways  Time is finite  Energy is expandable Energy is the capacity to do work.   4 sources of energy on a human:  physical (cuantum): nutrition, fitness, sleep, recovery. Emotional (Quality): how do you feel. Mental (Focus): one thing on a time, we are not multitasking. The Human Spirit (Purpose): aligment what you say its important and how you do   Renewal of energy its important, quality its the most important  Ultradian rhythms the 90-120 minute wave Paradigm Shift: Life as sprinter not a marathoner   To manage energy Optimally , we most build positive rituals  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Got You Here Won&#39;t Get You There</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/what-got-you-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2009 04:33:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/what-got-you-here/</guid>
      <description>Too often, succesfull people can&amp;rsquo;t tell the difference between wanting to win and wanting to win too much. The first part can be a good motivator but the secon is a problem.
 It was an interesting read, it make me realized the effect we have on people could bad if we focused on ourselves. It is important Listen and don&amp;rsquo;t try to add something to what other people say, just appreciate, say thanks and help if they ask, you are not a superman as you think you are, it is important to let them growth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marshall Goldsmith | Talk @ google</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/marshall-goldsmith-leading-at-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2009 08:57:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/marshall-goldsmith-leading-at-google/</guid>
      <description>I just discovered Marshall Goldsmith and he is awesome, looking forward to read his book What got you here, won&amp;rsquo;t get you there. Here are my takeaways:
 We spend a lot of time helping leaders learn what to do, we don&amp;rsquo;t spend enough time helping leaders learn what to stop -Peter Drucker WINNING TO MUCH, we are so competitive that we argue who is more miserable &amp;ldquo;help more, judge less&amp;rdquo; Use little amounts of money to produce change in behavior We only can change what we want to change.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>