<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>talks on Isaac Lopez</title>
    <link>https://rilopez.com/tags/talks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in talks on Isaac Lopez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 17:39:46 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rilopez.com/tags/talks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallel and Asynchronous Programming with Streams and CompletableFuture by Venkat Subramaniam</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/parallel-and-asynchronous-programming-venkat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 17:39:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/parallel-and-asynchronous-programming-venkat/</guid>
      <description>    parallel when you have an array of data concurrent when you have a problem that can be divided an conquer. Collection Pipeline pattern by Martin Flower forEachOrdered  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Mindfulness on Your Brain and Business by Dr Amishi jha</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/impact-of-mindfulness-on-your-brain-and-business-by-dr-amishi-hjha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 11:10:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/impact-of-mindfulness-on-your-brain-and-business-by-dr-amishi-hjha/</guid>
      <description>   My Takeaways  Presenter is Mario galarreta works in the people development team [23:50] Mindfulness is a mental mode characterized by attention to present moment experience without conceptual elaboration or emotional reactivity. [24:00] Be in the here and now without an story about it  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marshall Goldsmith | Talk @ google</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/marshall-goldsmith-leading-at-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2009 08:57:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/marshall-goldsmith-leading-at-google/</guid>
      <description>I just discovered Marshall Goldsmith and he is awesome, looking forward to read his book What got you here, won&amp;rsquo;t get you there. Here are my takeaways:
 We spend a lot of time helping leaders learn what to do, we don&amp;rsquo;t spend enough time helping leaders learn what to stop -Peter Drucker WINNING TO MUCH, we are so competitive that we argue who is more miserable &amp;ldquo;help more, judge less&amp;rdquo; Use little amounts of money to produce change in behavior We only can change what we want to change.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>