<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>talks on Isaac Lopez</title>
    <link>https://rilopez.com/tags/talks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in talks on Isaac Lopez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 23:19:31 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rilopez.com/tags/talks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Joe Rogan at Lex Podcast</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/joe-rogan-at-lex-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 23:19:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/joe-rogan-at-lex-podcast/</guid>
      <description>My takeaways Ideas breath in brains of humans. You just need to show up Joe Recommends Book The War of Art: Winning the Inner Creative Battle sit down and do the work, as a professional and wait for the muse (the idea) and let you know what to do. Joe met Jamie at the ice house he is unique , has little ego &amp;amp; is a great sound eng What is the meaning of life?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallel and Asynchronous Programming with Streams and CompletableFuture by Venkat Subramaniam</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/parallel-and-asynchronous-programming-venkat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 17:39:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/parallel-and-asynchronous-programming-venkat/</guid>
      <description> parallel when you have an array of data concurrent when you have a problem that can be divided an conquer. Collection Pipeline pattern by Martin Flower forEachOrdered </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microservices by Martin Flowler</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/microservices-by-martin-flowler/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 11:24:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/microservices-by-martin-flowler/</guid>
      <description>My takeaways: There is no real definition, Its something that from the begining is ill defined
Martin can identify 9 characteristics
Componentization via services Thinking about parts not as builders, but as users changing parts of stereo components Organized Around Business capabilities Smart endpoints and dump pipes. There is no room for complex middleware (ESB) Decentralized governance Decentraliced Data Managment Infraestructure automation Design for failure Are microservices just SOA? microservices is just a subset of SOA, but how bit should be to be called microservices</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Terrible Ideas Weakening Gen Z by Jonathan Haidt</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/three-terrible-ideas-weakening-gen-z-by-jonathan-haidt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 07:12:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/three-terrible-ideas-weakening-gen-z-by-jonathan-haidt/</guid>
      <description>My Takeaways Two disorders have been growing between generation Z
Emotional disorders: depression and anxiety Political polarization The sudden emergence of a new moral culture of safetyism (safespaces,trigger warinings, )
What does not kill you makes you weaker</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Mindfulness on Your Brain and Business by Dr Amishi jha</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/impact-of-mindfulness-on-your-brain-and-business-by-dr-amishi-hjha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 11:10:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/impact-of-mindfulness-on-your-brain-and-business-by-dr-amishi-hjha/</guid>
      <description> My Takeaways Presenter is Mario galarreta works in the people development team [23:50] Mindfulness is a mental mode characterized by attention to present moment experience without conceptual elaboration or emotional reactivity. [24:00] Be in the here and now without an story about it </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What You&#39;re Really Meant to Do | Robert Steven Kaplan </title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/what-you-are-really-meant-to-do-by-robert-steven-kaplan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 16:36:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/what-you-are-really-meant-to-do-by-robert-steven-kaplan/</guid>
      <description>My takeaways Speaker Robert Steven Kaplan &amp;ldquo;reaching your potential is a never ending activity&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;it is like being fit or healthy&amp;rdquo; You are not able to known your weakness. you need help from other people because we all have blind spots. ask for feedback on your weakness Why people fail (most commonly)? Isolation Inability to learn Knowing your self What is your life story? can you write down your success &amp;amp; failures narratives?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confessions of a Public Speaker by Scott Berkun</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/confessions-of-a-public-speaker-by-scott-berkun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2009 12:59:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/confessions-of-a-public-speaker-by-scott-berkun/</guid>
      <description>My takeaways Confessions of a public speaker book
6 reason of sucking at public speaking and how to fix it
Your are afraid of the crowd.Physical exercise that day
This is your first time. You&amp;rsquo;ve practiced till it&amp;rsquo;s good
You are a turtle on drugs. There is a rhythm I can follow
Rhythm is important ( not so fast, not so slow ) most people attention span is between 5 to 10 min, your talk should be sorted in segments of 5-10 mins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Energy Project by Tony Schwartz</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/the-energy-project-by-tony-schwartz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2009 15:50:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/the-energy-project-by-tony-schwartz/</guid>
      <description>My Takeaways Time is finite Energy is expandable Energy is the capacity to do work. 4 sources of energy on a human: physical (cuantum): nutrition, fitness, sleep, recovery. Emotional (Quality): how do you feel. Mental (Focus): one thing on a time, we are not multitasking. The Human Spirit (Purpose): aligment what you say its important and how you do Renewal of energy its important, quality its the most important Ultradian rhythms the 90-120 minute wave Paradigm Shift: Life as sprinter not a marathoner To manage energy Optimally , we most build positive rituals </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Arms, No Legs, No Worries by Nick Vujicic </title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/no-arms-no-legs-no-worries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2009 16:32:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/no-arms-no-legs-no-worries/</guid>
      <description>My takeaways Be grateful with what you are Do not think on what you do not have, think on what you have. Disabled is just in the mind Ask for a second opinion when somebody give you a bad opinion The day you think you reached your full potential, is the day when you haven&amp;rsquo;t done it. Live a life without limits </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marshall Goldsmith | Talk @ google</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/marshall-goldsmith-leading-at-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2009 08:57:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/marshall-goldsmith-leading-at-google/</guid>
      <description>I just discovered Marshall Goldsmith and he is awesome, looking forward to read his book What got you here, won&amp;rsquo;t get you there. Here are my takeaways:
We spend a lot of time helping leaders learn what to do, we don&amp;rsquo;t spend enough time helping leaders learn what to stop -Peter Drucker WINNING TO MUCH, we are so competitive that we argue who is more miserable &amp;ldquo;help more, judge less&amp;rdquo; Use little amounts of money to produce change in behavior We only can change what we want to change.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
