<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Isaac Lopez</title>
    <link>https://rilopez.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Isaac Lopez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 00:16:18 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rilopez.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Newsboat Macro Open Default Browser</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/newsboat-macro-open-default-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 00:16:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/newsboat-macro-open-default-browser/</guid>
      <description>My newsboat is configured to use w3m (a textonly browser) as default browser
browser &amp;#34;w3m %u&amp;#34; from times to times you enconter some pages that does not look good on text-only browser , this config defines a macro to open the default browser by pressing ,m (COMMA + lowercase m)
macro m set browser &amp;#34;xdg-open %u&amp;#34;; open-in-browser ; set browser &amp;#34;w3m %u&amp;#34; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Log Outgoing Node Http Requests</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/log-outgoing-node-http-requests/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 09:31:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/log-outgoing-node-http-requests/</guid>
      <description>This morning I had to debug a node proxy and needed to verify the external service request
function requestLogger(httpModule){ var original = httpModule.request httpModule.request = function(options, callback){ console.log(options.href||options.proto+&amp;#34;://&amp;#34;+options.host+options.path, options.method) return original(options, callback) } } requestLogger(require(&amp;#39;http&amp;#39;)) source: stackoverflow</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Difftool</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/git-difftool/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 12:15:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/git-difftool/</guid>
      <description>I am so used to work with jetbrain tools that I seldom use git diff and almost never configure and special diff tool. Today I learned how to setup meld as diff tool,
I added this settings to my ~/.gitconfig
[diff] tool = meld [difftool] prompt = false [difftool &amp;#34;meld&amp;#34;] cmd = meld &amp;#34;$LOCAL&amp;#34; &amp;#34;$REMOTE&amp;#34; You can change the order of the diff panes by changing the meld command arguments</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bazel Docker Install Sqlite</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/bazel-docker-install-sqlite/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 23:17:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/bazel-docker-install-sqlite/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago the bazel docker rules did not allow the use of RUN because of two main reasons:
 Virtually everything folks do in RUN isn&amp;rsquo;t reproducible. The way the Docker daemon evaluates RUN is never reproducible.  Fortunately that changed, now they provide rules not only to RUN (and create commits/layers) but also specific rules to download &amp;amp; install system packages.
Here an example on how to install sqlite into a ubuntu base image</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Svg Masks</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/svg-masks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 22:47:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/svg-masks/</guid>
      <description>Today after some pain learned how to create a mask to &amp;ldquo;carve&amp;rdquo; a hole with a given shape
&amp;lt;html&amp;gt; &amp;lt;body style=&amp;#34;background: url(&amp;#39;https://64.media.tumblr.com/7bed8273f621486faecdd407969aef51/tumblr_otfcxeacdO1slhhf0o1_1280.jpg&amp;#39;) center center / cover no-repeat;&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;svg className=&amp;#34;text-demo&amp;#34; viewBox=&amp;#34;0 0 600 400&amp;#34; width=&amp;#34;600&amp;#34; height=&amp;#34;400&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;defs&amp;gt; &amp;lt;mask id=&amp;#34;text-mask&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;rect width=&amp;#34;100%&amp;#34; height=&amp;#34;100%&amp;#34; fill=&amp;#34;white&amp;#34; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;text x=&amp;#34;60&amp;#34; y=&amp;#34;220&amp;#34; id=&amp;#34;mySubtext&amp;#34; style=&amp;#34;font-size: 150px; font-weight: bold;&amp;#34;&amp;gt; A Mask &amp;lt;/text&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/mask&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/defs&amp;gt; &amp;lt;ellipse cx=&amp;#34;300&amp;#34; cy=&amp;#34;200&amp;#34; rx=&amp;#34;300&amp;#34; ry=&amp;#34;150&amp;#34; fill=&amp;#34;white&amp;#34; mask=&amp;#34;url(#text-mask)&amp;#34; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/svg&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/html&amp;gt; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Henry Ford: My Life And Work</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/my-life-and-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 23:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/my-life-and-work/</guid>
      <description>Father was Farmer, Henry was more interested in using machines to do the work. Started by repairing watches, and although he liked the engineering craftsmanship required to make a great watch he had the preference to work on machines that help to make and activity more efficient.
Power and machinery, money and goods, are useful only as they set us free to live. They are but means to an end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kissinger: A Biography</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/kissinger-a-biography/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 13:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/kissinger-a-biography/</guid>
      <description>WII German Refuge, Academic, Womanizer, Foreign policy expert
Real politik based on practical rather than moral or ideological considerations, countries that act according to ideals instead of real interest are dangerous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joe Rogan at Lex Podcast</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/joe-rogan-at-lex-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 23:19:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/joe-rogan-at-lex-podcast/</guid>
      <description>My takeaways  Ideas breath in brains of humans.  You just need to show up Joe Recommends Book The War of Art: Winning the Inner Creative Battle  sit down and do the work, as a professional and wait for the muse (the idea) and let you know what to do.     Joe met Jamie at the ice house  he is unique , has little ego &amp;amp; is a great sound eng   What is the meaning of life?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idea Makers by Stephen Woldfram</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/idea-makers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 11:00:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/idea-makers/</guid>
      <description>I just read the book Idea Makers: Personal Perspectives on the lives Ideas of some notable People by Stephen Wolfram and it is amazing. Here some of my takeaways
  John von Newumann: when John died He left his daughter a Box that should be opened on the 50th anniversary of his death, his Daughter emailed Stephen that disappointingly the box was not John von Newman&amp;rsquo;s at all!
  There is a lot much more about Ada Lovelace, the first programmer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neuralink Summer 2020</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/neuralink-summer-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 23:40:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/neuralink-summer-2020/</guid>
      <description>My takeaways  Neuralink had a great streaming showing their latest updates they showed live telemetry directly from an alive walking pig Pigs are similar to people, they move a lot and they are robust so if the device does not get malfunctions on pigs , it would work on people Currently the team is 100 people, it is expected to grow up to 10K people the device uses something like bluetooth Clinical trial is aimed at people with paraplegia In the future you can record your memories and play it back, How do we know that this moment is not our future self playing back his memories?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Total Recall My Unbelievably true life story</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/total-recall/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 04:19:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/total-recall/</guid>
      <description>One of the first movies that I watch in a beta video format was Terminator, I remember going to my friends house, it was amazing, a very real Robot killing everyone was very memorable for my young mind. One of the scenes I remember the most was when the terminator steals a car, Arnold describes that that scene was filmed without city permission and very quick.
Arnold have had an exceptional life, one of the anecdotes I liked the most was after being questioned about a hidden message (I, F, Y) to lawmakers, and that it could not be a coincidence because the chance of that happened by coincide was very low, Arnold answered by asking</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stories of Your Life and Others</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/stories-of-your-life-and-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 14:55:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/stories-of-your-life-and-others/</guid>
      <description>The book is a collection of short science fiction stories, each more mind blowing than the other.
  Tower Of Babylon describes the construction of the tower from the point of view of a miner, in the right moment of reaching heaven
  Understand
  Division by Zero
  Story of your life The movie arrival was based in this story. Languages shape how you think, would you think similar to aliens if you could learn their Language?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leonardo Da Vinci</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/leonardo-da-vinci/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 04:54:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/leonardo-da-vinci/</guid>
      <description>Any Walter Isaacson&amp;rsquo;s biography is a warranty of delivering a bio research with story-telling structure and, This book was not the exception.
Although a lot has been writing about Leonardo Da Vinci, I was only familiar with his amazing notebooks and his famous paintings, but little I new about other important parts of this life like:
 Niccolò Machiavelli was his close friend. Closes a job request letter (to Ludovico Sforza) with something like &amp;ldquo;By the Way I am also a painter&amp;rdquo; Was an eternal procastinator His most important talent was his observation skills  You can find out more about the book on</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallel and Asynchronous Programming with Streams and CompletableFuture by Venkat Subramaniam</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/parallel-and-asynchronous-programming-venkat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 17:39:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/parallel-and-asynchronous-programming-venkat/</guid>
      <description>    parallel when you have an array of data concurrent when you have a problem that can be divided an conquer. Collection Pipeline pattern by Martin Flower forEachOrdered  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microservices by Martin Flowler</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/microservices-by-martin-flowler/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 11:24:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/microservices-by-martin-flowler/</guid>
      <description>My takeaways:   There is no real definition, Its something that from the begining is ill defined
  Martin can identify 9 characteristics
 Componentization via services Thinking about parts not as builders, but as users changing parts of stereo components Organized Around Business capabilities Smart endpoints and dump pipes. There is no room for complex middleware (ESB) Decentralized governance Decentraliced Data Managment Infraestructure automation Design for failure    Are microservices just SOA?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Terrible Ideas Weakening Gen Z by Jonathan Haidt</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/three-terrible-ideas-weakening-gen-z-by-jonathan-haidt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 07:12:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/three-terrible-ideas-weakening-gen-z-by-jonathan-haidt/</guid>
      <description>My Takeaways   Two disorders have been growing between generation Z
 Emotional disorders: depression and anxiety Political polarization    The sudden emergence of a new moral culture of safetyism (safespaces,trigger warinings, )
  What does not kill you makes you weaker
    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academy Lessons Learned</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/academy-lessons-learned/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 14:56:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/academy-lessons-learned/</guid>
      <description>Nearsoft Academy: Lessons learned after almost a decade preparing interns With a tight talent market, developing talent in-house gets a special appeal. Not only because of the reduction of costs but for the opportunity to rise the bar for future generations. Some assumptions anybody makes when trying to implement an internship program are,
 We can ask our seniors to mentor interns We are better at teaching than their university professors With the right training program any college graduate can produce good work at our organization  After almost a decade of working with interns, at Nearsoft academy We learned a lot of hard lessons that help us to get rid of those assumptions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Finances With Ledger</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/personal-finances-with-ledger/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 16:46:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/personal-finances-with-ledger/</guid>
      <description>Where my money went this time? That is always my question every time I take a look to my monthly bank statements. Over the years I have tried several apps and methods to reduce the panic we get when we have no idea how we acquired that credit card debt, Although all the options have its pros &amp;amp; cons, commonly they share the same problem of locking your data to their chooses proprietary format, giving you the risk of not being able to read when the online service disappears or the app no longer run on newer OS or devises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nearsoft Academy</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/nearsoft-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 21:42:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/nearsoft-academy/</guid>
      <description>8 years ago I started the foundations of our internship program at nearsoft, called Nearsoft Academy. So far 91 young engineers have taken the program, most of them worked for us right after graduation.
Designing an internship program Because I think that a software engineer is most about people than about &amp;ldquo;techy stuff&amp;rdquo;, I tried to design the program following the teachings several books like fearless change, pragmatic programmer, outliers &amp;amp; code complete</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile Is Dead by Dave Thomas</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/agile-is-dead-by-dave-thomas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 21:46:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/agile-is-dead-by-dave-thomas/</guid>
      <description>My Takeaways   UML destroyed the OOP by focusing a generation of programmers into Classes instead of objects.
  Agile is not a noun, it is an adjective
  Fear sells: new words, new roles, new ways to measure, are we doing it right?
  Cool sells: bright &amp;amp; Shiny, feeling the power, What!!, you aren&amp;rsquo;t doing Agile!!
  Agile is an industry, that taxes us in terms of fear</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Mindfulness on Your Brain and Business by Dr Amishi jha</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/impact-of-mindfulness-on-your-brain-and-business-by-dr-amishi-hjha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 11:10:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/impact-of-mindfulness-on-your-brain-and-business-by-dr-amishi-hjha/</guid>
      <description>   My Takeaways  Presenter is Mario galarreta works in the people development team [23:50] Mindfulness is a mental mode characterized by attention to present moment experience without conceptual elaboration or emotional reactivity. [24:00] Be in the here and now without an story about it  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make It Stick: The Science of Successful Learning</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/make-it-stick/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 02:15:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/make-it-stick/</guid>
      <description>Some random general highlights
 The most important is to fight forgetfulness. Learning styles is a myth, there are preferences but there is not true that some people learn better with a given kind of material (listening, reading, etc) Recalling and reflection is better than massive practice, the later gives the illusion of knowing by familiarizing the student with the material but the forgetfulness is quicker  Learning is misunderstood when we ask people about the best(preferred) learning method, most people will answer that it would be re-reading and highlight the material, but this approach is not backed up by data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peak Secrets From New Science of Expertise</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/peak-secrets-from-new-science-of-expertise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 02:46:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/peak-secrets-from-new-science-of-expertise/</guid>
      <description>Some random hightlights   Anything can be learned with a good designed deliverate practice
  the 10,000 hours myth (popularized by Malcom Gladwell) has been doing more harm than good, because it is not the time you put into something but how &amp;amp; what you practice
  deliberate practice is how anything can be learn. the components of a deliberate practice are:
 A well defined practice plan, with small steps or goals Proper Feedback (in a timely manner) Monitor your progress Mantain motivation Full Attention Mental Models should be considered    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deliberate Practices for programmers</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/deliberate-practices-for-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 02:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/deliberate-practices-for-programmers/</guid>
      <description>Per Dayra Chiu recommendation , last year I read the book Peak: Secrets from the New Science of Expertise by by K. Anders Ericsson &amp;amp; Robert Pool. I didn&amp;rsquo;t imagine how much gold I would find in that book. the topic that surprised the most was: Deliberate practices
First, what is deliberate practice? Is a special type of practice that is purposeful and systematic. It is highly demanding mentally so it requires high levels of focus and concentration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 18:47:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Me in 10 secs Software engineer, Educator, avid student of life.
Long version I am a life long learner, currently working as software engineer contractor.
As an Application Developer and Project Manager I have an agile and pragmatic approach to my craft. I have created a wide variety of business applications, with a particular interest in web apps and database design using Java, Go, JavaScript and PostgreSQL.
Sometime ago I started the Nearsoft Academy, a training program to help recent graduates become world-class software engineers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 18:47:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>I love hearing from people, so please email me at isaac@rilopez.com and introduce yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impediment to Action Advances Action</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/impediment-to-action-advances-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 15:33:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/impediment-to-action-advances-action/</guid>
      <description>While it is true that someone can impede our actions, they can not impede our intentions and our attitudes, which have the power of being conditional and adaptable. For the Mind converts any obstacle to its action into means of achieving it. That which is an impediment to action advances action , What stands in the way becomes the way
Marcus Aurelius, Meditations 5.20
 How many times we forget this?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philosophy Is for Life</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/philosophy-is-for-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 12:58:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/philosophy-is-for-life/</guid>
      <description>Philosophy is not a trick to catch the public; it is not devised for show. it is non concerned with words, but with facts. It&amp;rsquo;s not employed for some pleasure before day is spent, or to relieve the uneasiness of our leisure. It shape and built up the soul, it gives order to live guides action, shows what should and shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be done. &amp;ndash; it sits at the rudder steering our course as we vacillate in uncertanties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toma Al Toro Por Los Cuernos</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/toma-al-toro-por-los-cuernos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 12:38:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/toma-al-toro-por-los-cuernos/</guid>
      <description>You have endured countless troubles &amp;ndash; all for not letting your ruling reason do the work it was made for&amp;ndash; Enough already &amp;mdash; Marcus Aurelius, Meditations, 9.26
 In Spanish there is this saying &amp;ldquo;toma al toro por los cuernos&amp;rdquo; to indicate to take charge of the problem/issue/task in front. In this quote Marcus indicate that we should do it always using our ruling reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feeling good. The new mood therapy </title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/feeling-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 05:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/feeling-good/</guid>
      <description>This book help me to understand and work out some of my mental patterns by reframing cognitive distortions. In some sense your mind&amp;rsquo;s goal on creating this distortions is to protect you from emotional danger. But as with anything in life it can go sideways, if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t get check and balances
  All-or-Nothing Thinking: Your brain categorizes everything in Black or White, Good or Bad. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t realized that everything has more gradients and nothing is absolute</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Mans War</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/old-mans-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 04:08:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/old-mans-war/</guid>
      <description>Space travel is controlled by The colonian defence forces( a Human military organization) , but everyone in earth does not know much about it, its technology is so advanced that scientist at earth does non understand how it works.
Only the elder are allowed to enlist the space force , having the promise of cures for they sick bodies. The book narrates the enlistment and adventures of John Perry (a 75 year old writer)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linda Rising Interview</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/linda-rising-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/linda-rising-interview/</guid>
      <description>I read the book fearless change almost 8 years ago and since then I have been a big follower of Linda Rising teachings. Because one of my new-year resolutions was to meet at least one of my heros, I asked Carlos (from dojo live) to help me talk to Linda Rising, I was not hoping he could get her as a guess in dojo live,.. ohh I was very very wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning new tricks - JHipster: AngularJS, Spring Boot</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/jaimito-el-cartero-oriented-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/jaimito-el-cartero-oriented-programming/</guid>
      <description>I have always thought that the best motivator to learn something is when somebody pays you for doing it (indirectly). Last year I accepted a small freelance project just because it would be a good oportinity to sharp skills and add something new to my bag of tricks. Since for sometime I have been using some &amp;ldquo;outdated&amp;rdquo; things (Ember.js, ColdFusion, Node.js , YUI Library), so I thought &amp;ldquo;it would be cool to use something &amp;ldquo;mainstream/popular&amp;rdquo; with younger developers, and I got surprised because I found something that had all of that and it was a cool name: JHipster</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What You&#39;re Really Meant to Do | Robert Steven Kaplan </title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/what-you-are-really-meant-to-do-by-robert-steven-kaplan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 16:36:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/what-you-are-really-meant-to-do-by-robert-steven-kaplan/</guid>
      <description>My takeaways  Speaker Robert Steven Kaplan &amp;ldquo;reaching your potential is a never ending activity&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;it is like being fit or healthy&amp;rdquo; You are not able to known your weakness. you need help from other people because we all have blind spots. ask for feedback on your weakness Why people fail (most commonly)?  Isolation Inability to learn   Knowing your self  What is your life story? can you write down your success &amp;amp; failures narratives?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confessions of a Public Speaker by Scott Berkun</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/confessions-of-a-public-speaker-by-scott-berkun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2009 12:59:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/confessions-of-a-public-speaker-by-scott-berkun/</guid>
      <description>My takeaways   Confessions of a public speaker book
  6 reason of sucking at public speaking and how to fix it
  Your are afraid of the crowd.Physical exercise that day
  This is your first time. You&amp;rsquo;ve practiced till it&amp;rsquo;s good
  You are a turtle on drugs. There is a rhythm I can follow
 Rhythm is important ( not so fast, not so slow ) most people attention span is between 5 to 10 min, your talk should be sorted in segments of 5-10 mins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Energy Project by Tony Schwartz</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/the-energy-project-by-tony-schwartz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2009 15:50:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/the-energy-project-by-tony-schwartz/</guid>
      <description>My Takeaways  Time is finite  Energy is expandable Energy is the capacity to do work.   4 sources of energy on a human:  physical (cuantum): nutrition, fitness, sleep, recovery. Emotional (Quality): how do you feel. Mental (Focus): one thing on a time, we are not multitasking. The Human Spirit (Purpose): aligment what you say its important and how you do   Renewal of energy its important, quality its the most important  Ultradian rhythms the 90-120 minute wave Paradigm Shift: Life as sprinter not a marathoner   To manage energy Optimally , we most build positive rituals    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Arms, No Legs, No Worries by Nick Vujicic </title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/no-arms-no-legs-no-worries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2009 16:32:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/no-arms-no-legs-no-worries/</guid>
      <description>My takeaways  Be grateful with what you are Do not think on what you do not have, think on what you have. Disabled is just in the mind Ask for a second opinion when somebody give you a bad opinion The day you think you reached your full potential, is the day when you haven&amp;rsquo;t done it. Live a life without limits    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Got You Here Won&#39;t Get You There</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/what-got-you-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2009 04:33:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/what-got-you-here/</guid>
      <description>Too often, successful people can&amp;rsquo;t tell the difference between wanting to win and wanting to win too much. The first part can be a good motivator but the secon is a problem.
 It was an interesting read, it make me realized the effect we have on people could bad if we focused on ourselves. It is important Listen and don&amp;rsquo;t try to add something to what other people say, just appreciate, say thanks and help if they ask, you are not a superman as you think you are, it is important to let them growth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outliers: The Story of Success</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/outliers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/outliers/</guid>
      <description>I have read this book, but haven&amp;rsquo;t write my opinion about it
You can find out more about the book on
 Wikipedia page Amazon Page Goodreads page  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marshall Goldsmith | Talk @ google</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/posts/marshall-goldsmith-leading-at-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2009 08:57:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/posts/marshall-goldsmith-leading-at-google/</guid>
      <description>I just discovered Marshall Goldsmith and he is awesome, looking forward to read his book What got you here, won&amp;rsquo;t get you there. Here are my takeaways:
 We spend a lot of time helping leaders learn what to do, we don&amp;rsquo;t spend enough time helping leaders learn what to stop -Peter Drucker WINNING TO MUCH, we are so competitive that we argue who is more miserable &amp;ldquo;help more, judge less&amp;rdquo; Use little amounts of money to produce change in behavior We only can change what we want to change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fearless Change: Patterns for Introducing New Ideas</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/fearless-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2006 09:19:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/fearless-change/</guid>
      <description>This book resonated a lot with me. Suddenly I realized that there is a way to introduce changes in any human organization. I have been working on government systems for 2 years and started to see a now way out. I am looking forward to put in practice the patterns.
Here some patterns that I found interesting:
 Just Do It: Don’t wait for the perfect moment when you have the resources and knowledge you think you need; instead, take the first baby step and start learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pragmatic Programmer</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/pragmatic-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2005 22:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/pragmatic-programmer/</guid>
      <description>this is my go to reference book for any software engineering work/life problem. it contains a lot of wisdom gathered from the tranches of multiple software projects
Some tips/phrases I remember the most:
 Mob programming: when more than two programmers work in the same code, same time. Take responsibility, provide options , Don&amp;rsquo;t make lame excuses Stone soup and boiled frogs Invest regularly in your knowledge portfolio Good design is easier to change than bad design Orthogonality: in geometry two lines are orthogonal if they meet at right angles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Complete</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/code-complete/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2005 22:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/code-complete/</guid>
      <description>I have read this book, but haven&amp;rsquo;t written my opinion about it
You can find out more about the book on:
 Wikipedia page Amazon Page Goodreads page  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>