<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books I’ve read on Isaac Lopez</title>
    <link>https://rilopez.com/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books I’ve read on Isaac Lopez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 18:47:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rilopez.com/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Total Recall My Unbelievably true life story</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/total-recall/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 04:19:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/total-recall/</guid>
      <description>One of the first movies that I watch in a beta video format was Terminator, I remember going to my friends house, it was amazing, a very real Robot killing everyone was very memorable for my young mind. One of the scenes I remember the most was when the terminator steals a car, Arnold describes that that scene was filmed without city permission and very quick.
Arnold have had an exceptional life, one of the anecdotes I liked the most was after being questioned about a hidden message (I, F, Y) to lawmakers, and that it could not be a coincidence because the chance of that happened by coincide was very low, Arnold answered by asking</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stories of Your Life and Others</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/stories-of-your-life-and-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 14:55:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/stories-of-your-life-and-others/</guid>
      <description>The book is a collection of short science fiction stories, each more mind blowing than the other.
  Tower Of Babylon describes the construction of the tower from the point of view of a miner, in the right moment of reaching heaven
  Understand
  Division by Zero
  Story of your life The movie arrival was based in this story. Languages shape how you think, would you think similar to aliens if you could learn their Language?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leonardo Da Vinci</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/leonardo-da-vinci/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 04:54:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/leonardo-da-vinci/</guid>
      <description>Any Walter Isaacson&amp;rsquo;s biography is a warranty of delivering a bio research with story-telling structure and, This book was not the exception.
Although a lot has been writing about Leonardo Da Vinci, I was only familiar with his amazing notebooks and his famous paintings, but little I new about other important parts of this life like:
 Niccolò Machiavelli was his close friend. Closes a job request letter (to Ludovico Sforza) with something like &amp;ldquo;By the Way I am also a painter&amp;rdquo; Was an eternal procastinator His most important talent was his observation skills  You can find out more about the book on</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make It Stick: The Science of Successful Learning</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/make-it-stick/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 02:15:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/make-it-stick/</guid>
      <description>Some random general highlights
 The most important is to fight forgetfulness. Learning styles is a myth, there are preferences but there is not true that some people learn better with a given kind of material (listening, reading, etc) Recalling and reflection is better than massive practice, the later gives the illusion of knowing by familiarizing the student with the material but the forgetfulness is quicker  Learning is misunderstood when we ask people about the best(preferred) learning method, most people will answer that it would be re-reading and highlight the material, but this approach is not backed up by data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peak Secrets From New Science of Expertise</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/peak-secrets-from-new-science-of-expertise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 02:46:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/peak-secrets-from-new-science-of-expertise/</guid>
      <description>Some random hightlights   Anything can be learned with a good designed deliverate practice
  the 10,000 hours myth (popularized by Malcom Gladwell) has been doing more harm than good, because it is not the time you put into something but how &amp;amp; what you practice
  deliberate practice is how anything can be learn. the components of a deliberate practice are:
 A well defined practice plan, with small steps or goals Proper Feedback (in a timely manner) Monitor your progress Mantain motivation Full Attention Mental Models should be considered    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feeling good. The new mood therapy </title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/feeling-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 05:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/feeling-good/</guid>
      <description>This book help me to understand and work out some of my mental patterns by reframing cognitive distortions. In some sense your mind&amp;rsquo;s goal on creating this distortions is to protect you from emotional danger. But as with anything in life it can go sideways, if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t get check and balances
  All-or-Nothing Thinking: Your brain categorizes everything in Black or White, Good or Bad. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t realized that everything has more gradients and nothing is absolute</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Mans War</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/old-mans-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 04:08:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/old-mans-war/</guid>
      <description>Space travel is controlled by The colonian defence forces( a Human military organization) , but everyone in earth does not know much about it, its technology is so advanced that scientist at earth does non understand how it works.
Only the elder are allowed to enlist the space force , having the promise of cures for they sick bodies. The book narrates the enlistment and adventures of John Perry (a 75 year old writer)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Got You Here Won&#39;t Get You There</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/what-got-you-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2009 04:33:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/what-got-you-here/</guid>
      <description>Too often, succesfull people can&amp;rsquo;t tell the difference between wanting to win and wanting to win too much. The first part can be a good motivator but the secon is a problem.
 It was an interesting read, it make me realized the effect we have on people could bad if we focused on ourselves. It is important Listen and don&amp;rsquo;t try to add something to what other people say, just appreciate, say thanks and help if they ask, you are not a superman as you think you are, it is important to let them growth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outliers: The Story of Success</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/outliers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/outliers/</guid>
      <description>I have read this book, but haven&amp;rsquo;t write my opinion about it
You can find out more about the book on
 Wikipedia page Amazon Page Goodreads page  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fearless Change: Patterns for Introducing New Ideas</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/fearless-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2006 09:19:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/fearless-change/</guid>
      <description>This book resonated a lot with me. Suddenly I realized that there is a way to introduce changes in any human organization. I have been working on government systems for 2 years and started to see a now way out. I am looking forward to put in practice the patterns.
Here some patterns that I found interesting:
 Just Do It: Don’t wait for the perfect moment when you have the resources and knowledge you think you need; instead, take the first baby step and start learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pragmatic Programmer</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/pragmatic-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2005 22:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/pragmatic-programmer/</guid>
      <description>this is my go to reference book for any software engineering work/life problem. it contains a lot of wisdom gathered from the tranches of multiple software projects
Some tips/phrases I remember the most:
 Mob programming: when more than two programmers work in the same code, same time. Take responsibility, provide options , Don&amp;rsquo;t make lame excuses Stone soup and boiled frogs Invest regularly in your knowledge portfolio Good design is easier to change than bad design Orthogonality: in geometry two lines are orthogonal if they meet at right angles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Complete</title>
      <link>https://rilopez.com/books/code-complete/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2005 22:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rilopez.com/books/code-complete/</guid>
      <description>I have read this book, but haven&amp;rsquo;t written my opinion about it
You can find out more about the book on:
 Wikipedia page Amazon Page Goodreads page  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>